Guide to the Trade catalogs collection.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- W
  - West Disinfecting Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1905; Uai W52; 1 volume (Box 347, Folder 4004)
    Fumigating apparatus, etc.
  - West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company (Tyrone, Pa.), 1941; Uai W5216; 1 volume (Box 347, Folder 4005)
    Timber for paper production
  - Westcott Chuck Company (Oneida, N.Y.), 1892–1902; Uai W522; 3 volumes (Box 347, Folder 4006)
    Chucks
  - Western Auto Supply Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1930–1932; Uai W523; 3 volumes (Box 347, Folder 4007-4008)
  - Western Block Company (Lockport, N.Y.), 1904; Uai W524; 1 volume (Box 347, Folder 4009)
    "Anvil" tackle blocks
  - Western Camera Manufacturing Company (Chicago, Ill.), undated; Uai W5245; 1 volume (Box 347, Folder 4010)
    "Cyclone" cameras and photographic supplies
  - Western Cement Association (Louisville, Ky.), 1886; Uai W5246; 2 volumes (Box 347, Folder 4011)
  - Western Edison Light Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1893; Uai W5248; 1 volume (Box 347, Folder 4012)
    Edison lighting systems
  - Western Electric Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), Uai W5249
    Telephone supplies, dynamos, motors, etc.
    - 1908, 3 volumes (Box 371)
    - 1912, 1 volume (Box 372)
    - 1915, 1 volume (Box 373)
  - Western Mineral Wool Company (Cleveland, Ohio, etc.), 1888; Uai W5253; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4013)
    Mineral wool insulation
  - Western Pearl Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1891; 1 volume (Box 399, Folder 4368)
  - Western Soil Bacteria Company (San Francisco, Calif.), 1915; Uai W5259; 4 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4014)
    "Westobrac"
  - Western Tool and Manufacturing Company (Springfield, Ohio), 1923; Uai +W526; 2 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4015)
    Tools, etc.
  - Western Toy Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1884–1889; Uai W5262; 2 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4016)
  - Western Union, undated; 1 volume (Box 399, Folder 4369)
    Telegrams, etc.
  - Western Wheel Works (Chicago, Ill., New York, N.Y.), 1896; 1 volume (Box 399, Folder 4370)
  - Western Wheeled Scraper Company (Aurora, Ill.), undated; Uai W5267; 3 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4017)
    Grading and road marking machinery
  - Westinghouse Air Brake Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), Uai +W528
    Air signal apparatus, valves, etc.
    - 1882–1907, 7 volumes (Box 360, Folder 4188-4192)
    - 1904, 1 volume (Box 361)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation (East Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1944; Uai +W52823; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4019)
    Ignitron rectifiers
  - Westinghouse Electric Supply Company (Springfield, Ohio, etc.), 1940–1949; Uai +W5283; 6 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4020-4021)
    Lamps, etc.
  - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company (Newark, N.J.), 1941; Uai +W52819; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4018)
  - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company (Pittsburgh, Pa., etc.), Uai +W5282
    Motors, lighting systems, etc.
    - 1893–1900, 21 volumes (Box 362, Folder 4193-4197)
    - 1900–1905, 16 volumes (Box 363, Folder 4198-4203)
    - 1906–1942, 34 volumes (Box 364, Folder 4204-4209)
    - 1940, 1 volume (Box 365)
  - Westinghouse Machine Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1882–1900; Uai W5284; 3 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4022)
    Westinghouse engines, steam turbines, etc.
  - Westinghouse Traction Brake Company (New York, N.Y.), 1904; Uai +W5286; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4023)
    Westinghouse brakes for electric railway service
  - Weston Electrical Instrument Company (Newark, N.J.), 1908–1914; Uai +W529; 11 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4025-4030)
    Switchboard indicating instruments
  - Weston, Byron, Company (Dalton, Mass.), 1941; Uai +W5288; 10 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4024)
  - Wetmore-Savage Company (Boston, Mass.), 1911–1924; Uai +W534; 6 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4031-4033)
    Motor boat supplies and accessories, etc.
  - Wharton, William, Jr. (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1867; Uai W555; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4034)
    Railroad safety switch
  - Wheeler Reflector Company (Boston, Mass.), 1912–1929; Uai +W567; 3 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4039-4040)
    Lighting equipment, etc.
  - Wheeler, C. H., Manufacturing Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1921; Uai W5616; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4035)
    Condensing equipment
  - Wheeler, E. S., and Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1905; Uai +W5618; 1 volume (Box 374)
  - Wheeler, Edmund (London, England), 1876; Uai W562; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4036)
    Microscopic objects
  - Wheeler, Russel, and Son (Utica, N.Y.), 1895; Uai W564; 2 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4037-4038)
    Furnaces, stoves, hot water boilers, etc.
  - Wheeler-Schebler Carburetor Company, Inc. (Indianapolis, Ind.), 1917; Uai W568; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4041)
    "Schebler" carburetor
  - Wheeling Corrugating Company (Wheeling, W. Va., etc.), 1897; Uai +W57; 2 volumes (Box 375)
    Sheet metal and sheet metal goods
  - Whitall Tatum Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1905–1908; Uai +W581; 3 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4044)
    Chemical glassware, etc.
  - Whitall, Tatum and Company (Philadelphia, Pa., etc.), 1876–1898; Uai +W58; 5 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4042-4043)
  - White Company (Cleveland, Ohio), Uai +W5825
    Trucks, fire apparatus, etc.
    - 1946, 2 volumes (Box 376)
    - 1946, 1 volume (Box 377)
  - White Manufacturing Company (Bridgeport, Conn.), 1886–1900; Uai +W585; 17 volumes (Box 348, Folder 4051-4057)
    Coach and carriage lamps and mountings
  - White Manufacturing Company (Bridgeport, Conn.), 1901–1906; Uai +W585; 6 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4058-4060)
  - White Sewing Machine Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1892–1900; Uai W5854; 4 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4062)
    Sewing machines and bicycles
  - White, A. J. (London, England), 1883–1884; Uai W5824; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4045)
    Seigel's curative syrup, shaker extract, etc.
  - White, George E., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1866; Uai W583; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4047)
  - White, H. C., Company (North Bennington, Vt.), 1907; Uai W5835; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4048)
    Stereographs and lantern slides
  - White, J., 1892; Uai W5837; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4049)
    Electric instruments
  - White, James (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1899; Uai +W584; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4050)
    Sheet metal architectural ornaments
  - White, O. C., Company (Worcester, Mass.), undated; Uai W5853; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4061)
    Adjustable fixtures
  - White, S.S., Dental Manufacturing Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1866; Uai +W5828; 1 volume (Box 348, Folder 4046)
    Operative instruments, accessories, appliances, and materials
  - White-house Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1930–1947; Uai +W5874; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4065)
  - Whitehead Metal Products Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai W5872; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4064)
    Metal goods
  - Whitehead and Hoag Company (Newark, N.J.), 1927; Uai +W587; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4063)
    Ribbon, metal and celluloid badges, etc.
  - Whitin Machine Works (Whitinsville, Mass.), 1915; Uai W589; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4067)
    Cotton card-room machinery
  - Whitley, William (London, England), 1882; Uai W588; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4066)
    Grocery provisions
  - Whitman Saddle Company (New York, N.Y.), 1896; Uai W596; 3 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4071)
    Saddles, bridles, crops, bicycles, etc.
  - Whitman and Barnes Manufacturing Company (Akron, Ohio), 1909–1910; Uai +W595; 4 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4068-4069)
    High speed tools
  - Whitman and Burrell (Little Falls, N.Y.), 1873–1878; Uai +W5953; 8 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4070)
    Cheese factory and creamery apparatus
  - Whitney Arms Company (New Haven, Conn., 1867–1884; Uai +W6154; 4 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4075)
  - Whitney Electrical Instrument Company (Boston, Mass.), 1893; Uai W616; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4076)
    Voltmeters, ammeters, and indicators
  - Whitney, Baxter D. (Winchendon, Mass.), undated; Uai W61; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4072)
  - Whitney, T. D. (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai W614; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4073)
    Housekeeping goods, embroidery goods, lace curtains, etc.
  - Whitney-Anderson Paper Company, Inc. (Springfield, Mass.), 1940; Uai W615; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4074)
  - Whittaker, Clark and Daniels, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1950; Uai W617; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4077)
    Minerals, colors, and pigments
  - Whittall, M. J., Associates (Worcester, Mass.), 1922; Uai W618; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4078)
  - Whittemore, Belcher and Company (Chicopee Falls, Mass.), 1874; Uai +W619; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4079)
  - Whittlesey, Charles W., and Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1896; Uai W6195; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4080)
    Cameras and photographic materials
  - Wiener, Ernst, Company (New York, N.Y.), 1906; Uai W635; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4081)
  - Wier, Stephen M. (New Haven, Conn.), 1879; Uai W636; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4082)
  - Wiesenfeld, "little joe", Company (Baltimore, Md.), undated; Uai +W637; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4083)
    Saddles
  - Wightman, Joseph M. (Boston, Mass.), 1839–1858; Uai W639; 5 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4084-4085)
    Philosophical instruments, etc.
  - Wilbraham Brothers (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1876–1885; Uai W641; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4086)
    Baker rotary pressure blower, etc.
  - Wilckes, Joseph (New York, N.Y.), 1898; Uai +W642; 4 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4087)
    Arndt's "Econometer"
  - Wilcox Manufacturing Company (Aurora, Ill.), 1908; Uai W643; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4088)
    Le Roy house door hangers
  - Wiley and Russell Manufacturing Company (Greenfield, Mass.), 1914; Uai W648; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4089)
    Screw cutting tools and machinery
  - Wilfert, John, Company (New York, N.Y.), 1919; Uai W649; 1 volume (Box 379)
    Mill supplies and power transmission machinery
  - Wilkinson, A. J., and Company (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai W654; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4090)
  - Will Corporation (Rochester, N.Y.), 1939; Uai +W66; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4091)
    Chemical reagents
  - Will Young, Elmer G., and Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1895–1896; Uai +W687; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4108)
    Electrical and scientific instruments, etc.
  - Willans and Robinson, LD (Thames Ditton, Surrey, England), undated; Uai W661; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4092)
    "Willans" central-valve engine
  - Willcox Engineering Company (Saginaw, Mich.), undated; Uai W6645; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4094)
    Automatic water weigher
  - Willcox and Gibbs Sewing Machine Company (London, England), undated; Uai W664; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4093)
    Automatic sewing machines
  - Willer Manufacturing Company (Milwaukee, Wis.), 1895–1897; Uai +W667; 2 volumes (Box 380)
    Blinds and screens
  - Willey's Carbide Tool Company (Detroit, Mich.), 1947; Uai +W665; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4095)
    Radial and axle face mills
  - Willey, B. J. (Jeffersonville, Ind.), undated; Uai W669; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4096)
    Electrically driven machine tools
  - Williams Patent Crusher and Pulverizer Company, Inc. (St. Louis, Mo.), 1909; Uai +W676; 5 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4103-4104)
    Grinding machinery, etc.
  - Williams Typewriter Company (Derby, Conn., etc.), 1901; Uai W6765; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4105)
  - Williams and Clark Company (New York, N.Y.), 1887; Uai W675; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4100)
    Bone fertilizers
  - Williams, B. S., and Company (Kalamazoo, Mich.), 1885; Uai W671; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4097)
    Wind-mills, pumps, tanks, etc.
  - Williams, Brown and Earle (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1916; Uai +W6754; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4101)
    Stereopticons, magic lanterns and accessories
  - Williams, Brown and Earle, Inc. (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1926; Uai +W6755; 2 volumes (Box 349, Folder 4102)
    Dissecting instruments, etc.
  - Williams, G. M. (Hale Cliff, England), 1867; Uai W6716; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4098)
    Concrete stone
  - Williams, H. B., and Company (Rochester, N.Y.), undated; Uai W672; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4099)
    Boilers, marine and high-speed engines, etc.
  - Williamson Submarine Corporation (Norfolk, Va.), 1915; Uai +W677; 1 volume (Box 349, Folder 4106)
    Flexible tube and submarine work apparatus
  - Willimantic Thread Company (Willimantic, Conn.), 1877; Uai W678; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4107)
    Thread
  - Willys-Overland Company (Toledo, Ohio), 1915; Uai +W688; 8 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4109)
  - Wilmot Castle and Company (Rochester, N.Y.), undated; Uai W689; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4110)
    Arnold steam sterilizer
  - Wilson Automatic Water Still Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1900; Uai W694; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4112)
    Water distillation systems
  - Wilson Brothers (Easton, Pa.), 1911; Uai +W695; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4113)
    Grinding mills, bone cutters, etc.
  - Wilson Manufacturing Company (New London, Conn.), 1873; Uai W6964; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4117)
    People's mower
  - Wilson Mechanical Instrument Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1933; Uai +W6968; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4118)
    "Rockwell" hardness tester
  - Wilson Memindex Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1922; Uai W697; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4119)
    Filing systems, etc.
  - Wilson, Jas. G., Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1903; Uai W693; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4111)
    Flooring, awnings, and cabinet work, etc.
  - Wilson-Jones Loose Leaf Company (Chicago, Ill., New York, N.Y.), 1915–1917; Uai W6955; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4114-4115)
    Loose leaf binders and systems
  - Wilson-Maeulen Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1928; Uai +W696; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4116)
    Pyrometers, "Rockwell" hardness tester, etc.
  - Winchester Repeating Arms Company (New Haven, Conn.). Catalogs, 1876–1894; Uai +W7212; 15 volumes (Box 366, Folder 4210-4224)
    Guns, ammunition, etc.
  - Winchester Repeating Arms Company (New Haven, Conn.). Catalogs, 1896–1920; Uai +W7212; 4 volumes (Box 367, Folder 4225-4228)
  - Winchester Repeating Arms Company (New Haven, Conn.). Miscellaneous publications, 1869–1939; Uai +W7212; 19 volumes (Box 369, Folder 4241-4259)
  - Winchester Repeating Arms Company (New Haven, Conn.). Price Lists, 1885–1899; Uai +W7212; 12 volumes (Box 368, Folder 4229-4240)
  - Winship, Charles (New Haven, Conn.), 1857–1858; Uai W732; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4120)
    Self-ventilating refrigerators
  - Winship, Chas. A., and Company (Chicago, Ill.), undated; Uai W7322; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4121)
    Jewelry, pins, medals, etc.
  - Winship, W. W., Company (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai W7325; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4122)
    Automobile trunks and equipment
  - Winslow Boiler and Engineering Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1924; Uai W733; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4123)
    "Kleen-Heet" oil burning system
  - Winslow Brothers Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1909; Uai W7333; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4124)
    Ornamental iron and bronze work, elevator-door operating device, etc.
  - Winsted Hardware Manufacturing Company (Winsted, Conn.), undated; Uai +W7336; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4125)
    "Durabilt" folding iron
  - Winter Brothers Company (Wrentham, Mass.), 1914–1915; Uai +W734; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4126)
    Taps and dies
  - Winthrop Chemical Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1938–1940; Uai +W737; 9 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4127)
  - Winton Bicycle Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1897; Uai +W7373; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4128)
  - Winton Engine Works (Cleveland, Ohio), 1946; Uai +W7375; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4129)
    Diesel type marine oil engine
  - Winton Motor Carriage Company, 1903; Uai +W738; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4130)
    Winton touring car
  - Wiremold Company (Hartford, Conn.), 1930; Uai W743; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4131)
    Wiremold conduit fittings
  - Wirt, Charles (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1896; Uai W746; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4132)
    "Wirt" dynamo brush
  - Withmore Feeds (Malden, Mass.), 1946; Uai W7465; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4133)
    Poultry management goods
  - Wittnauer, A., Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1925; Uai W786; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4134)
    "Longines" watches
  - Wittstock, P. and R. (Berlin, Germany), 1897–1898; Uai W788; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4135)
  - Woburn Degreasing Company of New Jersey (Harrison, N.J.), 1943; Uai +W813; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4136)
  - Wolcott, undated; Uai +W83; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4137)
    "Wolcott" filters, faucets and attachments
  - Wolf's Head Oil Refining Company, Inc., 1941; Uai W833; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4139)
    Motor oil
  - Wolff, R. H., and Company, Ltd. (New York, N.Y.), 1898–1900; Uai W832; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4138)
  - Wolz, Max (Bonn a. Rh., Germany), 1887; Uai W839; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4140)
  - Wood Conversion Company (St. Paul, Minn.), 1941; Uai W8565; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4152)
    Nu-wood for wainscoting, etc.
  - Wood Drill Works (Paterson, N.J.), 1911; Uai W857; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4153)
    Drills, mining machinery, etc.
  - Wood Hydraulic Hoist and Body Company (Detroit, Mich.), 1933; Uai +W8575; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4154)
    "Tempered-Aire" air conditioning system
  - Wood, Edward, George (London, England), 1859; Uai W851; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4141)
    Cameras and photographic materials, etc.
  - Wood, N. G., and Sons (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai W852; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4142)
    Prize cups, etc.
  - Wood, P. K. (Los Angeles, Calif.), 1899; Uai W853; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4143)
    Propeller pump
  - Wood, R. D., and Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1903–1906; Uai +W854; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4144-4145)
    "Mond" gas, hydraulic machinery, etc.
  - Wood, Walter A., Mowing and Reaping Machine Company (Hoosick Falls, N.Y.), 1869–1911; Uai +W855; 11 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4146-4150)
  - Wood, Wm. H., Loco Fire Box and Tube Plate Company (Media, Pa.), 1910–1912; Uai +W8556; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4151)
  - Wood-mosaic Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1897; Uai +W858; 1 volume (Box 381)
    Parquetry, wood flooring
  - Woodin and Little (San Francisco, Calif.), 1893; Uai W8578; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4155)
    Windmills and pumps, etc.
  - Woodruff, Miller and Company (Mount Carmel, Conn.), 1884–1887; Uai W86; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4156-4157)
    Carriage goods
  - Woodruff, Walter W., and Sons Company (Mount Carmel, Conn.), 1898–1900; Uai +W861; 5 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4158-4159)
  - Woods, Benj. O., and Company (Boston, Mass.), 1877; Uai +W862; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4160)
    Printing supplies
  - Woods, S. A., Machine Company (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai +W869; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4162)
  - Woods, Sherwood and Company (Lowell, Mass.), 1876; Uai W867; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4161)
    Sherwood's standard white lustral wire ware
  - Woolman, G. S. (New York, N.Y.), 1879; Uai W885; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4163)
    Microscopes and optical instruments
  - Woolson, Orosco C. (New York, N.Y.), 1914; Uai W887; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4164)
    "E-Z Set" pipe covering and boiler accessories
  - Worthington Pump and Machinery Corporation (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1924–1944; Uai +W8982; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4166)
    Diesel engines, hydraulic machinery, etc.
  - Worthington Pumping Engine Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1900; Uai W8983; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4167)
    Pumping engines, etc.
  - Worthington, Henry R., Hydraulic Works (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1881; Uai +W898; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4165)
    Pumping engines, steam pumps, and hydraulic machinery
  - Worthy Paper Company (West Springfield, Mass.), 1940–1950; Uai W8993; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4168-4169)
  - Wright Aeronautical Corporation (Paterson, N.J.), 1928–1929; Uai +W930; 4 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4170)
    Airplanes, aviation engines, etc.
  - Wright Aeronautical Corporation (Paterson, N.J.), 1931; Uai +W936; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4172)
    Airplanes, etc.
  - Wright Manufacturing Company (Detroit, Mich.), undated; Uai W937; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4174)
    "Wright" steam specialties
  - Wright and Ditson (Boston, Mass., etc.), 1928; Uai W9363; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4173)
    Athletic and sporting goods
  - Wright, Nelson (New York, N.Y.), 1864; Uai W934; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4171)
    Globe lenses, photographic apparatus, etc.
  - Wrought Iron Range Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1892–1911; Uai +W947; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4175)
    Wrought steel ranges
  - Wurlitzer, Rudolph, Manufacturing Company (Cincinnati, Ohio), 1930; Uai +W963; 1 volume (Box 350, Folder 4176)
    "Wurlitzer" pianos
  - Wyckoff, Seamans and Benedict (New York, N.Y.), 1897; Uai W972; 3 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4177)
    Remington typewriters
  - Wyman and Gordon (Worcester, Mass.), 1887; Uai W98; 2 volumes (Box 350, Folder 4178)
    Quick-action vises and screw vises
- X
  - XL Refrigerating Company, Inc. (Chicago, Ill.), undated; Uai +X1; 3 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4260)
    Ice making and refrigerating machinery, etc.
- Y
  - Yale Caster Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1883; Uai Y123; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4261)
  - Yale Iron Works (New Haven, Conn.), undated; Uai +Y126; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4262)
  - Yale Lock Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1871–1881; Uai +Y13; 3 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4263)
    Locks and hardware, etc.
  - Yale Lock Manufacturing Company (Stamford, Conn.), 1882; 2 volumes (Box 399, Folder 4371)
    Lifts and hoists
  - Yale and Towne Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), Uai Y12
    - 1905–1921, 7 volumes (Box 383, Folder 4283-4286)
    - 1909, 1 volume (Box 384)
    - 1910, 1 volume (Box 385)
    - 1910, 1 volume (Box 386)
    - 1921, 1 volume (Box 387)
  - Yale and Towne Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1917; Uai Y122; 1 volume (Box 388)
  - Yawman and Erbe Manufacturing Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1908–1909; Uai Y29; 2 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4264)
  - Yeates and Son (Dublin, Ireland), undated; Uai Y376; 3 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4265)
    Opticians' supplies
  - Yellow Pine Manufacturers' Association, 1906; Uai +Y38; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4266)
    Yellow pine moldings
  - Yost Manufacturing Company (Toledo, Ohio), 1897; Uai Y82; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4267)
    "Falcon" bicycles
  - Youmans, Daniel D. (New York, N.Y.), 1895–1900; Uai Y83; 3 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4268)
  - Young and Sons (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1884; Uai Y88; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4269)
    Surveyors' compasses, chain tapes, etc.
  - Yuba Manufacturing Company (San Francisco, Calif.), 1940; Uai +Y9; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4270)
    Dredges
- Z
  - Zane, J., and Company (Boston, Mass.), 1885; Uai +Z16; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4271)
    "Sanitary" water closet
  - Zantzinger, George B., and Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1896; Uai +Z17; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4272)
    Zantzinger refrigeration system
  - Zeiss, Carl (Jena, Germany), 1885–1888; Uai +Z36; 5 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4273-4275)
    Microscopes, microscopical accessories, etc.
  - Zenith Carburetor Company (Detroit, Mich., etc.), 1919; Uai Z43; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4276)
    Carburetors
  - Zentmayer, Joseph (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1895; Uai Z46; 2 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4277)
    Microscopes, optical instruments, etc.
  - Zimmer and Company (Frankfort, Germany), 1939; Uai Z65; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4278)
    Euquinine
  - Zimmermann, E. (Leipzig and Berlin, Germany), 1925; Uai Z66; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4279)
  - Ziv Steel and Wire Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1927; Uai Z69; 1 volume (Box 382, Folder 4280)
    "Zivco", "Wizard", tool steel, etc.
  - Zouri Drawn Metals Company (Chicago Heights, Ill.), 1921–1925; Uai +Z79; 2 volumes (Box 382, Folder 4281-4282)
    Safety key-set store front construction
- Catalog cards (Box 406)